(星期六 1955年11月12日)
(晚上10点03分)
博士
Doc!
博士 博士
Doc! Doc! Doc!
- 博士 博士! - 什么事?
- Doc! Doc! - What?
别紧张 博士 是我 马丁!
Okay, relax, Doc. It's me. It's me! It's Marty.
不 不可能 我刚刚才把你送回未来
No, it can't be. I just sent you back to the future.
我知道 你有
Yeah. No, I know. You did send me
把我送回未来去 但我回来了
back to the future, but I'm back.
我又从未来回来了
I'm back from the future.
我的天!
Great Scott!
《回到未来3》
孩子们 现在是什么时间?
Hey, kids, what time is it?
你好杜德时间!
Howdy Doody time!
我的天!
Great Scott!
你好杜德时间?
It's Howdy Doody Time
鲍勃和杜德 向你问好
Bob Smith and Howdy Do Say Howdy Do to you
你好杜德时间?
Howdy Doody time?
日期 星期日 1955年11月13日
Date. Sunday, November 13, 1955. 7:01 a.m.
昨晚的时光旅行实验
Last night's time travel experiment
显然获致了彻底的成功
was apparently a complete success.
闪电在十点零四分整击中钟塔
Lightning struck the clock tower at precisely 10:04 p.m.
将不可或缺的十亿瓦特电量 输进时光旅行车
Sending the necessary 1.21 gigawatts into the time vehicle,
使其在一道灿烂的闪光中消失
which vanished in a brilliant flash of light
在地上留下两条燃烧的胎痕
leaving a pair of fire trails behind.
我因此估计马丁和时光旅行车
I, therefore, assume that Marty and the time vehicle
已穿越时空回到了1985年
were transported forward through time into the year 1985.
在那之后...
After that...
我记不得在那之后发生了什么
After that, I can't recall what happened.
事实上 我甚至不记得我是怎么回到家的
In fact, I don't even remember how I got home.
或许是那十亿瓦特的电压
Perhaps the gigawatt discharge
加上那时光旅行车所形成的
coupled with the temporal displacement field
变位力场
generated by the time vehicle
对我的脑波造成了伤害
caused a disruption of my own brain waves
造成了短暂的失忆现象
resulting in a condition of momentary amnesia.
但 我现在已经想起
Indeed, I now recall that moments
在时光旅行车消失在
after the time vehicle disappeared
未来之后
into the future,
我看见一幅马丁的影像
I saw a vision of Marty saying
告诉我他又从未来回来了
he had come back from the future.
嘿 博士
Hey, Doc!
毫无疑问的 这是某种幻觉...
Undoubtedly, this was some sort of residual image...
博士
Doc.
博士 冷静点好吗? 冷静点 是我 马丁
Doc, calm down, okay. Just calm down. It's me. It's Marty.
不! 不可能是你 我已经把你送回未来去了!
No, it can't be you! I sent you back to the future!
没错 博士
That's right, Doc. That's right,
但我又从未来回来
but I came back again. I came back from the future.
还记得昨晚的事吧?
Don't you remember last night?
你昏倒 我带你回来
You fainted. I brought you home.
这是不可能的! 你不可能在这里!
This can't be happening! You can't be here!
这完全不合理!
It doesn't make sense for you to be here!
我无法相信你会在这里!
I refuse to even believe that you are here!
博士 我在这里 这一切也很合理
Doc, I am here, and it does make sense.
我是和1985年的你
Look, I came back to 1955 again with you,
一起回到1955年来 因为我们得从贝夫手中抢回一本书!
the you from 1985, 'cause we had to get a book from Biff!
但在我拿到书后
So once I got the book back,
那个1985年的你
you, that is the you from 1985,
坐在那辆德罗林跑车上 车子被闪电击中
were in the DeLorean, and it got struck by lightning,
回到了1885年!
and you got sent back to 1885!
1885年?
1885?
这真是个令人感兴趣的故事 未来小子
It's a very interesting story, future boy,
但还有一点是说不通的
but there's just one little thing that doesn't make sense.
如果未来的我现在是在过去
If the me of the future is now in the past,
你怎么会知道这一切?
how could you possibly know about it?
你写了一封信给我
You sent me a letter.
"亲爱的马丁 如果我的计算正确
"Dear Marty, if my calculations are correct,
你将在看见德罗林跑车被闪电击中后
you will receive this letter immediately after
立刻收到这封信
you saw the DeLorean struck by lightning.
首先我要向你保证 我一切平安
First, let me assure you that I'm alive and well.
我过去八个月以来 都快乐地活在1885年
I've been living happily these past eight months in the year 1885.
那道击中德罗林跑车的闪电
The lightning bolt that hit the DeLorean
造成电力超载
caused a gigawatt overload
烧毁了时光旅行器的电路
which scrambled the time circuits,
触发通量电容器
activated the Flux Capacitor,
把我送回到1885年
and sent me back to 1885.
负载的电量造成时光旅行器短路
The overload shorted out the time circuits
并毁了飞行电路
and destroyed the flying circuits.
很不幸 这辆车再也不能飞了"
Unfortunately, the car will never fly again."
它真的飞起来了?
It actually flew?
是的 我们在21世纪初期
Yeah, we had a hover conversion done
将它改装成能飞的动力系统
in the early 21st century.
令人难以置信!
Incredible!
"我在此以铁匠的身份出现 藉以掩护我
"I set myself up as a blacksmith as a front
从事将时光旅行器修复的工作
while I attempted to repair the damage to the time circuits.
不幸的是 一切努力都是枉然的
Unfortunately, this proved impossible,
因为合适的零件
because suitable replacement parts
得要到1947年才会发明
will not be invented until 1947.
无论如何 我如今已经很能适应
However, I've gotten quite adept
钉马蹄铁和修蓬车的日子"
at shoeing horses and fixing wagons."
真叫人想不到!
1885! Amazing!
我真的回到当年的西部时代 并成为一个铁匠
I actually end up as a blacksmith in the Old West.
很正点吧?
Pretty heavy, huh?
"我已经把德罗林跑车埋在靠近靴子山老墓园的
"I have buried the DeLorean in the abandoned Delgado Mine
戴尔加多废矿坑内
adjacent to the old Boot Hill Cemetery
我已注明在信里所附的地图上
as shown on the enclosed map.
但愿它能原封不动地保存在那里
Hopefully, it should remain undisturbed
直到你在1955年将它掘出来
and preserved until you uncover it in 1955.
你会在车里找到修复的说明
Inside, you will find repair instructions.
我那位1955年的副本..." 就是我啊
My 1955 counterpart..." That's me.
"将能轻易地将它修复
"...should have no problem repairing it
让你开着它回到未来去
so that you can drive it back to the future.
在你回到1985年之后 就把这辆时光旅行车毁掉"
Once you have returned to 1985, destroy the time machine."
把它毁掉?
Destroy it?
是的 这说来话长 博士
Yeah. Well, it's a long story, Doc.
"千万不要 我再强调一次
"Do not, I repeat, do not attempt
不要企图回来这里救我
to come back here to get me.
我现在的生活很快乐 这里有着新鲜的空气 和广阔的生活空间
I am perfectly happy living in the fresh air and wide-open spaces.
我认为没有必要的时光旅行
And I fear that unnecessary time travel
只会对时空的连续性
only risks further disruption
造成更严重的破坏
of the space-time continuum.
还有 请替我照顾爱因斯坦"
And please take care of Einstein for me."
爱因斯坦?
Einstein?
他是你的狗 博士 1985年的你把你的狗命名为爱因斯坦
He's your dog, Doc. Einstein is what you call your dog in 1985.
"我知道你会给他一个舒服的窝
"I know you will give him a good home.
记着要每天带他去散步两次
Remember to walk him twice a day
而且他只喜欢罐头狗食
and that he only likes canned dog food.
以上是我要交待的事 请尊重我的意思 并确实做到
These are my wishes. Please respect them and follow them.
好了 马丁 我在此向你道别 并祝你能够平安回去
And so, Marty, I now say farewell and wish you Godspeed.
你一直是我忠实的好朋友
You've been a good, kind, and loyal friend to me,
你对我的一生带来重大的影响
and you made a real difference in my life.
我将永远珍惜我们的友谊
I will always treasure our relationship
回忆你我共渡的美好时光
and think on you with fond memories,
温暖的感受 将永远留在我心里的角落
warm feelings, and a special place in my heart.
你永远的朋友 艾米·L·布朗博士
Your friend in time, Doc Emmett L. Brown.
1885年9月1日"
September 1st, 1885."
我不知道我还能写出如此感人的信
I never knew I could write anything so touching.
我知道 博士 很感人的一封信
I know. I know, Doc. It's beautiful.
别难过 哥白尼
It's all right, Copernicus.
一切都将平安无事的
Everything is gonna be fine.
对不起 博士 这都是我的错 害你被困在那里
I'm sorry, Doc. It's all my fault you're stuck back there.
我不该让贝夫逮到的
I never should've let Biff get to me.
西部时代倒也不是最糟的
There are plenty worse places to be than the Old West.
我有可能会跑回黑暗时代
I could have ended up in the Dark Ages.
他们可能会把我当作异教徒
They probably would have burned me
绑在柱子上烧死
at the stake as a heretic or something.
我们来看这地图
Let's look at the map.
好 根据图上的记载 时光旅行车
All right, according to this, the time vehicle
被封在侧面的坑道里
is sealed off in a side tunnel.
我们可能得将它炸开
We may have to blast.
我想你这一炸把死人都吵醒了
I think you woke up the dead with that blast.
拿着这照相机 我要将这一切都记录下来!
Take this camera. I want to document everything!
这让我想起
This reminds me of the time
我当年企图到地心去探险
I attempted to reach the center of the Earth.
我看遍了我最喜欢的作家 儒勒凡尔纳的书
I'd been reading my favorite author, Jules Verne.
我花了几个星期来准备那次探险
I spent weeks preparing that expedition.
而我那回甚至还走不了这么远
I didn't even get this far.
但话又说回来 我当时才12岁
Of course, I was only 12 at the time.
你知道吗? 当年就是儒勒凡尔纳所写的书
You know, it was the writings of Jules Verne
对我的一生造成了深远的影响
that had a profound effect on my life.
当我11岁时 头一次读
It was when I was 11 that I first read
海底两万里
Twenty Thousand Leagues Under the Sea.
我当时就下定决心
It was then that I realized
我得将我的一生奉献给科学
that I must devote my life to science.
博士 过来看 你看这个
Doc, check it out. Look at this.
我名字的缩写!
My initials!
就和地心探险记一样!
Just like in Journey to the Center of the Earth!
这表示时光旅行车
That means the time machine
一定就在这里面!
must be right through this wall!
它已经被埋在此地 达70年2个月又13天之久
It's been buried in here for 70 years, two months, and 13 days.
真不简单!
Astounding!
"你可以看得出来 那道闪电
"As you see, the lightning bolt
让控制时光机器的积体电路板造成了短路
shorted out the time circuit control microchip.
附上的..."
The attached..."
电路图
Schematic.
"附上的电路图将可以让你以1955年的零件
"Schematic diagram will allow you to build a replacement unit
制造出一组替换的组件
with 1955 components,
如此将可恢复时光机器的功能"
thus restoring the time machine to perfect working order."
叫人难以相信这一小片破铜烂铁
Unbelievable that this little piece of junk
竟然会造成如此严重的问题
could be such a big problem.
难怪这玩意儿会坏掉
No wonder this circuit failed.
这上面写着"日本制造"
It says, "Made in Japan."
你这话是什么意思? 博士 最好的东西都是日本制的
What do you mean, Doc? All the best stuff is made in Japan.
叫人难以相信!
Unbelievable!
你知道 当我还是个孩子时
You know, when I was a kid,
总希望能成为一个牛仔
I always wanted to be a cowboy.
如今知道我将在过去渡过余生
And now, knowing I'm gonna spend my future in the past,
似乎不失为一个渡过退休后的日子的好方法
it sounds like a wonderful way to spend my retirement years.
我刚刚想到 马丁 既然我回到了1885年
It just occurred to me, Marty, since I end up in 1885,
或许我已经是个历史人物了
perhaps I'm now in the history books.
我在想
I wonder.
我如果到图书馆去 是否会在铁匠书里
Could I go to the library and look myself up
看到关于我的消息?
in the old newspaper archives?
我可不晓得 博士
I don't know, Doc.
你自己不是经常说
You're the one that's always saying, you know,
人不该对自己的命运知道太多?
it's not good to know too much about your own destiny.
你说的对 马丁 我已经知道太多了
You're right, Marty. I know too much already.
我想我还是别急着去
Better that I not attempt to uncover
知道自己将来的际遇
the circumstances of my own future.
哥白尼 来吧! 孩子
Copernicus. Come on, boy!
我去找他 博士 哥白尼!
I'll get him, Doc. Copernicus!
哥白尼 来吧 我们回家去
Copernicus, come on. Let's go home, boy.
哪里不对劲?
What's wrong?
哪里不对劲? 哥白尼 来吧
What's wrong, Copernicus? Come on.
来吧 我们回家去 来
Come on, let's go home. Come on. Come on.
(艾米·布朗长眠于此)
到这边来
Doc! Doc! Come here!
快!
Quick!
怎么了? 马丁 你脸上的表情活像见了鬼
What's wrong, Marty? You look like you've seen a ghost.
差不多 博士
You're not far off, Doc.
我的天!
Great Scott!
听听这上面写的
Check this out.
"死于1885年9月7日"
"Died September 7th, 1885."
那是在你写那封信后一个星期啊!
That's one week after you wrote the letter!
"挚爱的克蕾拉在此立碑 献上永恒的哀思"
"Erected in eternal memory by his beloved Clara."
谁是克蕾拉?
Who the hell is Clara?
马丁 拜托别挡在那里!
Marty, please don't stand there!
好的 抱歉
Oh! Right. Sorry.
我得再照一张相
I gotta get another picture.
"为了八十块钱 被贝夫·添南从背后射杀"?
"Shot in the back by Buford Tannen over a matter of $80"?
这算是哪门子的未来啊?
What kind of a future do you call that?
"贝夫·添南是个声名狼藉的枪手
"Buford Tannen was a notorious gunman
他的坏脾气和流口水的毛病
whose short temper and a tendency to drool
为他赢得了疯狗的外号
earned him the nickname Mad Dog.
他拔枪的速度很快
He was quick on the trigger
吹嘘自己杀过12个人
and bragged that he had killed 12 men
还不包括印第安人或中国人在内"
not including Indians or Chinamen."
有提到我吗? 我是那12个人中的一个?
Does it mention me? Am I one of the 12?
等等
Just a minute.
"但这说法无法得到证实
"However this claim cannot be substantiated,
因为在1884年添南射杀了一个
since precise records were not kept
写了一篇不利于他的文章的报社编辑后
after Tannen shot a newspaper editor
就再也无法保存正确的记录"
who printed an unfavorable story about him in 1884."
难怪我们什么也找不到你
That's why we can't find anything.
看
Look.
威廉·麦佛莱全家合照 是你的亲戚?
William McFly and family. Your relatives?
我的曾祖父是叫威廉
My great-grandfather's name was William.
这就是他 长得蛮帅的
That's him. Good-looking guy.
有麦佛莱家的记载 却没有姓布朗的
McFlys, but no Browns.
或许我们弄错了 博士
Well, maybe it was a mistake, Doc.
或许那不是你的坟墓
Maybe that grave wasn't yours.
那可能是1885年时的另一个艾米·布朗
There could've been another Emmett Brown back in 1885.
我不知道
No. I don't know.
镇上那时有你们家的亲戚吗?
Did you have any relatives here back then?
布朗家1908年才搬来希尔谷
The Browns didn't come to Hill Valley until 1908.
而且他们当时是姓逢·布朗斯
And then they were the von Brauns.
我父亲在第一次大战时改了名字
My father changed our name during the First World War.
博士 你看
Doc, look.
我的天 是我啊!
Great Scott, it's me!
那么这一切全都是真的了?
Then it is true, all of it.
我确实回到了那时代而且被枪杀
It is me who goes back there and gets shot.
这是不会发生的 博士
It's not gonna happen, Doc.
在你修好时光器回路
After you fix the time circuits
并给德罗林车装上新轮胎后
and put new tires on the DeLorean,
我就要回到1885年 把你带回来
I'm going back to 1885, and I'm bringing you home.
衣服还合身吗?
The clothes fit?
除了靴子外都还可以 博士 靴子紧了点
Yeah, everything except the boots, Doc. They're kind of tight.
你确定这些服饰都合乎史实吗?
I don't know. Are you sure this stuff is authentic?
当然了 你难道没看过西部电影?
Of course. Haven't you ever seen a Western?
是的 我看过 博土
Yeah, I have, Doc.
克林特·伊斯特伍德可不会穿上这种怪衣服
Clint Eastwood never wore anything like this.
克林谁?
Clint who?
是啊 你还没听过他的大名
That's right. You haven't heard of him yet.
马丁 你得穿上这只靴子
Marty, you have to wear the boots.
你不能穿这种未来派的东西
You can't wear those futuristic things back in 1885.
你甚至不该在1955年穿这个
You shouldn't even be wearing them here in 1955.
好吧 博士 我保证一到那里
All right, Doc. Look, as soon as I get there,
就把它们穿上
I'll put them on. I promise.
好 我想一切都就绪了
Okay. I think we're about ready.
我已经把油箱加满
I put gas in the tank.
你在未来穿的衣服也已打包好
Your future clothes are packed.
为了预防万一 我还替你的对讲机换上了新电池
Just in case, fresh batteries for your walkie-talkies.
对了 那个能飘浮的装置呢?
Oh! What about that floating device?
飞行滑板
Hoverboard. All right.
博士 从这里回希尔谷市
You know, Doc, it's gonna be a hell of a long walk
得走很久啊
back to Hill Valley from here.
但这是最安全的计划
It's still the safest plan.
我不能把你送回人口众多的地方
After all, we can't risk sending you back into a populated area
或是某个地理学上的不明地带
or to a spot that's geographically unknown.
你该不会想撞上一棵
You don't want to crash into some tree
曾经存在过的树吧?
that once existed in the past.
这是一大片开阔地
This was all completely open country,
当你抵达后将会有足够的空间
so you'll have plenty of run out space when you arrive.
记住 你要去的地方是没有路的
Remember, where you're going, there are no roads.
那边有个小山洞
There's a small cave over there
是个隐藏时光旅行车的好地方
which will be a perfect place to hide the time vehicle.
新的时光机器所装的真空管已经先暖过机了
Well, the new time circuit control tubes are warmed up.
时光旅行回路启动
Time circuits on.
我是在9月1日写那封信的
I wrote the letter on September 1st,
所以我送你回去第二天
so we'll send you back the very next day,
也就是9月2日 那天是星期
September 2nd. That's a Wednesday.
1885年9月2日 早上8点
September 2nd, 1885, 8:00 a.m.
我是在7号星期一那天被射杀的
I get shot on Monday the 7th,
所以你将有五天的时间来找我
so you have five days to locate me.
我那封信上说我是铁匠
According to my letter, I'm a blacksmith,
所以我可能会拥有一间打铁铺
so I probably have a shop somewhere.
你只要将时光旅行车
All you have to do is drive the time vehicle
朝那银幕开过去
directly toward that screen,
并加速到每小时88英里
accelerating to 88 miles an hour.
慢着 博士 如果我朝那银幕开过去
Wait a minute. Doc, if I drive straight towards the screen,
会撞上那些印第安人的
I'm gonna crash into those Indians.
马丁 你没有以四度空间的角度来思考
Marty, you're not thinking fourth-dimensionally.
你到时候将会回到1885年
You'll instantly be transported to 1885,
那些印第安人的画像不会在那里
and those Indians won't even be there.
是啊 那么
Right. Well.
为了我们两个 祝你好运
Good luck for both of our sakes.
我们在未来见
See you in the future.
你是说过去?
You mean the past.
正是
Exactly.
一路顺风! 马丁!
Happy trails, Marty!
准备好了? 马丁
Ready, Marty?
准备好了!
Ready!
预备!
Set!
加油 银马
Hi-ho, Silver.
印第安人!
Indians!
是那个山洞!
The cave!
冲锋!
Charge!
见鬼 骑兵队!
Shit! The cavalry!
该死! 我把油管弄破了
Damn, I ripped the fuel line.
麦姬 打些水来 这边有个人受伤了
Maggie! Fetch some water! We got a hurt man here.
妈 是你吗?
Mom! Mom, is that you?
别说话
There, there now.
你已经昏睡了将近六个钟头
You've been asleep for nearly six hours now.
我做了一个好可怕的梦
I had this horrible nightmare.
我..我梦见我在西部
I dreamed... I dreamed I was in a Western.
我被一大群印第安人追赶 还有一头熊
I was being chased by all these Indians and a bear.
你现在在麦佛莱农场
Well, you're safe and sound
是很平安的
here now at the McFly farm.
麦佛莱农场?
McFly farm?
你是我的... 你是我的...
Well, you're my... You're my, my...
你是谁啊?
Who are you?
我姓麦佛莱 麦姬·麦佛莱
The name is McFly. Maggie McFly.
麦佛莱? 麦姬?
McFly. Maggie?
是麦佛莱太太 别遗漏太太这个称呼
And that's Mrs. McFly, and don't you be forgetting the Mrs.
你又是叫什么名字? 先生
And what might your name be, sir?
我姓麦...
Well, it's...
伊斯特伍德
Eastwood.
克林特·伊斯特伍德
Clint Eastwood.
你的头撞伤了 伊斯特伍德先生
Well, you hit your head, Mr. Eastwood.
虽然不严重 但算你运气好
Not too serious, but lucky for you,
谢穆斯发现了你
Seamus found you when he did.
谢穆斯?
Seamus.
我丈夫
Me husband.
恕我失陪了 伊斯特伍德先生 我得去看威廉
You'll be excusing me, Mr. Eastwood, while I tend to William.
威廉?
William.
不要紧 威廉 不要紧
Oh, that's okay, Will. It's okay.
- 他就是威廉?  - 对
- That's William? - Aye.
威廉·西恩·麦佛莱 我们这个家族在美国出生的第一代
William Sean McFly, the first of our family to be born in America.
不要紧 威尔
It's okay, Will.
这位客人是克林特·伊斯特伍德先生
This here is Mr. Clint Eastwood here visiting.
他很喜欢你呢! 伊斯特伍德先生
He surely likes you, Mr. Eastwood.
麦姬
Maggie.
我猎到了晚餐
I've got supper.
我不是想打探你的隐私
I'm not one to pry into a man's personal affairs,
你是如何来到这偏僻的地方?
but exactly how is it that you came to be way out here
你既没有马 也没有靴子和帽子
without a horse, or boots, or a hat?
我的车...
Well, my car...
我的马病了 而且 一头熊把我的靴子吃了
Horse broke down, and a bear ate my boots,
至于帽子 我想我是忘了拿
and I guess I just forgot my hat.
你怎能忘掉帽子这么重要的东西?
How could you forget a thing like your hat?
你要点水吗?
Would you like some water?
好的
Yeah.
我看这样好了 伊斯特伍德先生
I'll tell you what I'll do, Mr. Eastwood.
我会帮你找到你那位铁匠朋友
I'll help you find your blacksmith friend.
你今晚可以睡在谷仓里
You can stay the night in the barn,
明天我带你到铁路那边去
and tomorrow I'll take you as far as the railroad tracks.
你可以顺着它走到镇上
You can follow them straight on into town.
我甚至可以送你一顶帽子
I'll even give you a hat.
这真是太好了 谢谢
That's great. Thanks.
亲爱的威廉
That's my William.
是的
Yes.
我想你会觉得谷仓够舒服的
I think you'll find the barn comfortable.
我养的猪可从没抱怨过
Never had any complaints about it from the pigs.
谢穆斯!
Seamus!
借一步说话
A word with you.
好的
Aye.
帮我抱他一下好吗?
Will you hold him for a minute?
你确定你这么做妥当吗
Are you sure you're not after bringing a curse on this house
随便收留一个陌生人?
taking him in like that?
他是个很古怪的年轻人
He's such a strange young man.
对 但我对他有种奇怪的感觉 麦姬
Aye. But I've just got a feeling about him, Maggie,
让我觉得照顾他是应该的
that looking after him is the right thing to do.
这点是很重要的
That it's important.
你好 兄弟
Hey, buddy.
你看这孩子跟他处得多好
Look how the baby takes to him.
小威尔一向不喜欢陌生人的
Little Will never takes to strangers.
这就好像 他跟我们有某种渊源似的
It's almost as if he's connected to us.
威尔
Hey, Will.
原来你就是我的曾祖父
So you're my great-grandfather.
麦佛莱家族在美国出生的第一代
The first McFly born in America.
而且你还尿在我的身上
And you peed on me.
(山谷镇)
给我肥皂 法兰克
Give us some soap.
拿去吧
Here you go.
(出差到海斯维尔执行臭罗麦克斯的绞刑)
看看谁进来了
Take a look and see what just breezed in the door.
我不晓得马戏团到镇上来了
Why, I didn't know the circus was in town.
这件衬衫八成是从一个死中国人身上剥下来的
Must have got that shirt off a dead Chinese.
要些什么? 陌生人
What will it be, stranger?
我要一杯冰水
I'll have ice water.
冰水?
Ice water?
Water?
冰水? 你如果要喝水
You want water, you better go dunk your head
到外面的马槽就有了
in the horse trough out there.
在这里 我们供应威士忌
In here, we pour whiskey.
对不起
Excuse me.
什么事?
For what?
我在找一位铁匠
I'm trying to find the blacksmith.
麦佛莱!
Hey, McFly!
我不是告诉过你别到这...
Thought I done told you never to come in...
你不是谢穆斯·麦佛莱
You ain't Seamus McFly.
但你长得蛮像他的
You look like him, though,
特别是配上那顶丑帽子
especially with that dog-ugly hat.
你是那土包子的亲戚吗?
You kin to that hay barber?
你叫什么名字? 小子
What's your name, dude?
马丁...
Marty...
伊斯特伍德
Eastwood.
克林特·伊斯特伍德
Clint Eastwood.
这是哪门子的名字啊?
What kind of stupid name is that?
我看他是畜栏跑出来的小畜生
I'd say he's the runt of the litter.
看 兄弟们 看见他这些白牙齿没?
Hey, now, boys, would you take a look-see at these pearly whites?
除了买来的假牙 我还没见过
Hell, I ain't seen teeth look that straight
这么白的牙齿呢
that weren't store-bought.
看他穿的平底鞋
Take a gander at them moccasins.
那是什么样的皮做的啊?
What kind of skins is them?
那上面写的字是什么意思?
What's that writing mean?
耐克? 这是什么?
"Nike"? What is that?
印第安土话?
Some sort of Injun talk or something?
酒保 我在找那个骗人的铁匠
Bartender, I'm looking for that no-good, cheating blacksmith.
你有看到他吗?
You seen him?
没有 添南先生 我没看见他
No, sir, Mr. Tannen. I have not.
添南
Tannen.
你就是疯狗添南
You're "Mad Dog" Tannen.
疯狗?
"Mad Dog"?
我痛恨这名字
I hate that name.
我痛恨它 你听见了没?
I hate it, you hear?
谁也不能叫我疯狗!
Nobody calls me "Mad Dog"!
特别是你这种没用的窝囊废
Especially not some duded-up, egg-sucking gutter trash.
给我跳舞!
Dance!
给我跳!
Come on!
给我跳! 小鬼 你可以跳得更好!
Come on, runt! You can dance better than that!
妈的
Shit.
你最好快逃命 小子
You better run, squirrel.
把他抓起来!
Get him!
我们盖了一栋新的法院
We got ourselves a new courthouse.
正好趁这机会执行绞刑!
High time we had a hanging!
天啊
God
看他在那里摇摆
Look at him swing.
是啊 这镇上好久没吊过人了!
Yeah, haven't had a hanging in a long time!
我可以在五百码外射中一只狗身上的虫子 添南
It'll shoot the fleas off a dog's back at 500 yards, Tannen,
我现在就瞄准着你的脑袋!
and it's pointed straight at your head!
你欠我钱 打铁的
You owe me money, blacksmith.
这话怎么说?
How do you figure?
我的马掉了一只马蹄
My horse threw a shoe.
既然当初是你替它钉的马蹄铁
And seeing as you was the one that done the shoeing,
你就得负责
I say that makes you responsible.
反正你也一直没付我工钱 我们顶多互不相欠
Well, since you never paid me for the job, I say that makes us even.
当我的马掉了马蹄时
Wrong! See I was on my horse
我正骑着它 你害我跌下马!
when it threw the shoe, and I got throwed off!
跌破一瓶
And that caused me to bust a perfectly
上好的肯塔基红眼
good bottle of fine Kentucky red eye.
所以在我算来 打铁的
So the way I figure it, blacksmith,
你得赔我五块威士忌的钱
you owe me $5 for the whiskey
再加上75块钱赔那匹马!
and $75 for the horse!
正好是八十块
That's the $80.
听着 如果你的马掉了马蹄铁
Look, if your horse threw a shoe,
把它带来 我再帮它钉一个
bring him back, and I'll reshoe him.
我已经射死那匹马了!
I done shot that horse!
那是你家的事 添南
Well, that's your problem, Tannen.
错了 该担心的是你
Wrong. That's yours.
从现在起 你在走路时最好留意你背后
So from now on, you better be looking behind you when you walk.
因为有天你的背上将会挨颗子弹
Because one day you're gonna get a bullet in your back.
博士!
Doc!
马丁 我已经清楚地告诉你别来这里
Marty, I gave you explicit instructions not to come here
要你直接回1985年去
but to go directly back to 1985.
我知道 博士 但我非来不可
I know, Doc, but I had to come.
但我还是很高兴能见到你 马丁
But it's good to see you, Marty.
马丁 你得换掉这身衣服才行
Marty, you're gonna have to do something about those clothes.
你如果这样在镇上到处走
You walk around town dressed like that,
你会挨子弹的
you're liable to get shot.
或者被吊死
Or hanged.
是哪个白痴给你穿这身衣服的?
What idiot dressed you in that outfit?
就是你
You did.
"为了八十块钱
"Shot in the back by Buford Tannen
被贝夫添南在背后射杀?
over a matter of $80,
9月7号"?
September 7"?
这不就是下个星期一吗
That's this Monday!
如今我倒希望我赔给他那些钱
Now I wish I'd paid him off.
这个挚爱的克蕾拉是谁?
And who's this beloved Clara?
我不认识任何姓克蕾拉的啊
I don't know anyone named Clara.
我也不晓得 博士
I don't know, Doc.
我还以为她是你的女朋友
I thought maybe she was a girlfriend of yours.
马丁 我回到1885年 并接触这个时代的人和物
Marty, my involvement in such a social relationship here in 1885
已经可能对时空的连续性带来毁灭性的后果了
could result in a disruption of the space-time continuum.
身为一个科学家 我是绝不可能冒这种险的
As a scientist, I can never take that risk.
特别是在我们经历了这一切之后
Certainly not after what we've already been through.
艾米!
Emmett!
艾米
Hello, Emmett.
休伯特
Hubert.
是市长
It's the mayor.
打扰一下 艾米
Excuse me, Emmett.
还记得在上星期的镇民大会上
Do you remember last week at the town meeting when you volunteered
你志愿到车站去
to meet the new schoolteacher
迎接新到任的老师吧?
at the station when she came in?
是的 我还记得
Oh, yes, quite so.
我们刚接到消息 她明天会到
Well, we just got word she's coming in tomorrow.
这是详细内容
Here are the details for you.
多谢你的热心协助
Thanks for all your help.
不客气 休伯特
Anytime, Hubert.
她的名字叫克雷顿小姐 克蕾拉·克雷顿
Oh! Her name's Miss Clayton. Clara Clayton.
博士 现在我知道克蕾拉是谁了
Well, Doc, now we know who Clara is.
马丁 这是不可能发生的
Marty, it's impossible.
这种我跟她会一见钟情的说法 根本就是浪漫派的鬼话
The idea that I could fall in love at first sight is romantic nonsense.
这种事根本没有科学理论根据
There's no scientific rationale for that concept.
别这样 博士 这又不是科学
Aw, come on, Doc. It's not science.
当你遇上了情投意合的女孩时 会像是被雷击中
You meet the right girl, it just hits you. It's like lightning.
马丁 拜托你 别再说了
Marty, please don't say that.
我和詹妮弗的情形就是这样
That's the way it was for me and Jennifer.
我们甚至无法将眼睛从对方的身上移开
I mean, we couldn't keep our eyes off each other.
老天 詹妮弗 该死的 希望她没事 博士
God, Jennifer, damn. I hope she's all right, Doc.
我不敢相信我们就这样把她丢在那门廊上
I can't believe we just left her there on the porch.
别担心 马丁 她不会有事的
Don't worry, Marty. She'll be fine.
当你在1955年把那本年鉴烧掉后
When you burned the almanac in 1955,
接下来的历史也都恢复正常了
the normal timeline was restored.
这表示当我们回到1985年时
That means once we're back in 1985,
你只需要到她家去叫醒她就行了
you just have to go over to her house to wake her up.
马丁 到那活塞那边去
Oh, Marty, turn that valve over there
向右转到底
all the way to the right.
对 转到底
Yeah, pull it all the way around.
好 开始了!
Okay. Let's go!
要来杯冰茶吗?
Iced tea?
不 谢谢
No, thanks.
这是个冰箱啊
It's a refrigerator.
看样子克雷顿小姐
Well, I guess Miss Clayton
得另外找别的交通工具了
will have to find other transportation.
如果我根本没碰上那女人
If I never meet the woman,
我就不可能跟她谈恋爱 对吧?
there's no possibility of a romantic infatuation, right?
- 全听你的 博士 - 好
- You're the doc, Doc. - All right.
我们去取回德罗林跑车然后回到未来去
We'll get the DeLorean and get ourselves back to the future.
对了 博士 我在抵达时
Oh, listen, Doc, I tore a hole
把油箱弄破了一个洞
in the gas tank when I was landing,
我们得把洞补起来再把油加满
so we're gonna have to patch it up and get some gas.
你是说那车里没有油了?
You mean we're out of gas?
没错 但没什么大不了的
Yeah, it's no big deal.
我们不是还有核融合反应器吗?
We've got Mr. Fusion, right?
核融合反应器提供时光旅行仪以及通量电容器的电力
Mr. Fusion powers the time circuits and the Flux Capacitor,
但内燃机却始终都是靠汽油做为动力的
but the internal combustion engine runs on ordinary gasoline.
一直都是
It always has.
这一带要到下个世纪
There's not gonna be a gas station around here
才会有加油站的设立
until sometime in the next century.
若是没有汽油
Without gasoline,
我们是无法将德罗林跑车推进到每小时88英里的
we can't get the DeLorean up to 88 miles per hour.
我们现在该怎么办?
So what do we do?
24里!
Twenty-four!
这是没有用的! 马丁
It's no use, Marty!
即使是世界上最快的马
Even the fastest horse in the world
时速顶多只有35或40英里!
won't run more than 35, 40 miles an hour!
酒保说这是他们最烈的酒
Bartender said that's the strongest stuff they got.
启动试试 马丁
Try it, Marty.
再加些油!
Give it more gas!
该死!
Damn!
我把喷射油管弄坏了
It blew the fuel injection manifold.
那玩意儿确实有够烈
Strong stuff, all right.
我得花一个月才能将它修好
It will take me a month to rebuild it.
一个月?
A month?
博士 你星期一就要被杀了啊!
Doc, you're gonna get shot on Monday!
我知道 我知道 我只希望...
I know! I know! I know! I wish...
慢着 我有办法了 我们可以将它从险坡上开下去!
Wait. I've got it! We can simply roll it down a steep hill!
不行 我们找不到够平的地方
Oh! We'd never find a smooth enough surface.
除非...
Unless...
地面结冰!
Of course! Ice!
我们等到冬天 等湖面结冰
We'll wait until winter when the lake freezes over.
冬天? 博士 你在说什么啊?
Winter? Doc, what are you talking about?
再三天就是星期一了好吧
Monday! It's three days away!
好的 好的
All right, all right, all right.
让我以逻辑的方法来想这件事
Just let's think this thing through logically.
我们已知道它无法以本身的动力前进
We know it won't run under its own power.
我们也知道无法用马来拖
We know we can't pull it.
但 如果我们能想出一个办法
But if we could figure out a way
将它推进到每小时88里的速度
to push it up to 88 miles an hour.
这就是了
That's it.
它能跑多快? 我自己就曾将它开到过55
How fast can she go? Why, I've had her up to 55 myself.
我听说无畏的法兰克·法戈
I heard that Fearless Frank Fargo
在车子开过维迪换车站之后
got one of these up to near 70
曾开到将近70里的速度
out past Verde Junction.
你认为有可能将它开到90里吗?
Do you think it's possible to get it up to 90?
90里?
Ninety?
我的天 老弟 有谁会这么急啊?
Tarnation, son, who'd ever need to be in such a hurry?
我跟他只是在打个赌罢了
It's just a little bet he and I have, that's all.
在理论上来说 这办得到吗?
Theoretically speaking, could it be done?
我想你若是开在平原上
Well, I suppose, if you had a straight
而且是直的铁轨
stretch of track with a level grade,
而且后面都没有拖着车厢
and you weren't hauling no cars behind you,
还能够将蒸汽锅炉烧得够热
and if you could get the fire hot enough.
我是指那种比炼狱之中还要热的热度
And I'm talking about hotter than the blazes of hell and damnation itself.
这一来它就有可能达到这速度
Then yes, sir, it might be possible to get her up that fast.
下一班火车何时会经过此地?
Tell me, when does the next train come through here?
星期一早上八点
Monday morning at 8:00.
这里! 这条由主线分出的支线
Here. This spur that runs off the main line
在到达克雷顿峡谷前有三里的路
three miles out to Clayton Ravine.
那是一条平坦笔直的铁轨
It's a long stretch of level track
而且在1985年时仍然存在
that will still exist in 1985.
我们将在此地用火车头来推德罗林跑车
This is where we'll push the DeLorean with the locomotive.
奇怪的是 这张地图上把克雷顿峡谷 叫做修那许峡谷
Funny. This map calls Clayton Ravine Shonash Ravine.
这八成是它以前的印第安旧名字 再完美不过了
That must be the old Indian name for it. It's perfect.
一条长长的直铁轨
A nice long run that goes clear across
直通到峡谷上头的铁桥
the bridge over the ravine,
你知道 靠近希尔戴尔社区一带
you know, over near that Hilldale housing development.
没错 博士 但根据这份地图上的记载 那里没有桥
Right, Doc, but according to this map, there is no bridge.
博士 我们可以打消那个主意了
Well, Doc, we can scratch that idea.
我们不能等上一年半载
I mean, we can't wait a year and a half
等这座桥完成
for this thing to get finished.
马丁 这是完美的
Marty, it's perfect.
你只是没有以四度空间来思考
You're just not thinking fourth-dimensionally.
是的 我在这方面确实比较不行
Right. Right. I have a real problem with that.
你还不明白吗 这座桥在1985年是存在的啊
Don't you see? The bridge will exist in 1985.
不但安全牢固 而且还在使用
It's safe and still in use.
因此 只要我们能在到达峡谷前
Therefore, as long as we get the DeLorean up to 88 miles an hour
将德罗林跑车推进到88英里
before we hit the edge of the ravine,
我们就会在一瞬间到达
we'll instantaneously arrive at a point in time
那座桥已经完成的年代
where the bridge is completed.
车子底下将会有铁轨 然后安全地滑过峡谷的上空
We'll have track under us and coast safely across the ravine.
那个火车头呢?
What about the locomotive?
它将会在峡谷底下撞个稀烂
It will be a spectacular wreck.
可惜到时候将没有人看见这一切
Too bad no one will be around to see it.
救命啊! 救命!
Help me! Help!
我的天
Great Scott!
来! 这边
Here
快点!
Hurry!
跳上来!
Jump!
谢谢你 先生 你救了我的...
Thank you, sir. You saved my...
...命
...life.
艾米·布朗在此听候差遣 小姐是...
Emmett Brown at your service, Miss...
克雷顿
Clayton.
克蕾拉·克雷顿
Clara Clayton.
克蕾拉!
Clara!
好美的名字
What a beautiful name.
我能帮你把行李搬进去吗?
May I help you inside with these?
不用了 我自己来就可以
Oh, no, that won't be necessary. I can take care of it.
你已经帮了我很多忙了
You've done more than enough already.
但这真的一点也不麻烦
But it's really no trouble.
博士 她说不用了 我们该走了
Doc, she says it's fine, and we got to get going.
小姐 祝你教学顺利 一切平安
Ma'am, good luck with your school teaching and everything.
克蕾拉 我会去找史戴勒先生
Clara, I'll straighten everything out
解释那辆出租马车损毁的经过
with Mr. Statler for the buckboard rental.
你不必担心
Don't worry about that.
我觉得在某方面来说 我该对此事负责
I feel somewhat responsible for what happened.
你这么做真是绅士的风度 布朗先生 艾米
That would be very gentlemanly of you, Mr. Brown. Emmett.
你知道吗? 我得感谢
You know, I'm almost glad
那条蛇吓到了马
that snake spooked those horses.
否则我们可能永远不会认识
Otherwise, we might never have met.
我想这一切都是缘份吧
I suppose it was destiny.
那么 谢谢你帮了这么多忙
Well, thank you for everything.
请别客气
You're quite welcome.
我还会再见到你 对吧?
I will see you again, won't I?
当然 我相信你会经常见到我的
Of course. You'll see lots of me.
我肯定 我在镇上有个店
I'm sure. I have a shop in town.
我是本地的科学家 铁匠
I'm the local scientist, blacksmith.
科学? 哪方面的科学
Science? What sort of science?
天文学? 化学?
Astronomy? Chemistry?
事实上 我研究各方面的科学
Actually, I'm a student of all sciences.
博士 我们得走了
Hey, Doc, we got to get going.
是啊 那么 恕我们失陪了 克蕾拉
Oh, yes. Well, excuse us, Clara.
我们得...走了
We have to get going.
再见
Toodle-oo.
你说你会经常见到她是什么意思 博士?
What do you mean, you're gonna be seeing lots of her, Doc?
我改天可能会顺路来看看她
Well, I might see her again just in passing.
少来了 博士 你有看见她看着你的眼神吗?
Come on, Doc. Did you see the way she was looking at you?
她刚刚受了很大的惊吓 对吧?
She did have quite a scare, right?
不管怎样 这位克雷顿小姐
After all, Miss Clayton almost ended up
差点就摔死在克雷顿峡谷底呢
at the bottom of Clayton Ravine.
克雷顿峡谷
Clayton Ravine.
我的天! 博士 克雷顿峡谷是以一个教师的名字命名的
Holy shit. Hey, Doc, Clayton Ravine was named after a teacher.
他们说她是在一百年前跌下那里
They say she fell in there 100 years ago.
一百年前? 那就是今年啊!
100 years ago! That's this year!
学校里每个人都知道这故事
Every kid in school knows that story,
我们心目中总会希望某个老师
'cause we all have teachers
也摔到峡谷里去
we'd like to see fall into the ravine.
我的天!
Great Scott!
那么她是应该跟着那马车一起跌下去的
Then she was supposed to go over in that wagon.
这下子我可能已经严重地改变了历史
Now I may have seriously altered history.
听着 博士 最坏的情况是什么?
Look, Doc, what's the worst that can happen, huh?
顶多不以她的名字替那峡谷命名
So they don't name the ravine after her.
我们还是快把德罗林车弄好
Let's just get the DeLorean ready
离开这地方
and get the hell out of here.
我真希望我从来没有发明那不祥的时光机器
I wish I'd never invented that infernal time machine.
它只会带来灾难而已
It's caused nothing but disaster.
博士 这是马丁
Doc, Doc, this is Marty.
你听见了吗?
Do you read me? Over.
没问题 马丁
Check, Marty.
好极了 博士 它们仍然能用
Great, Doc. These things still work.
好 马丁
All right, Marty.
我们再把全部的计划演练一遍
Once more, let's go over the entire plan and layout.
很抱歉 这模型做得太简陋...
I apologize for the crudity of this model, but I just...
我知道 博士 它不合比例 没有关系 博士
Yeah, I know, Doc. It's not to scale. It's okay, Doc.
好 明天晚上 星期天
All right. Tomorrow night, Sunday,
我们将把德罗林跑车 放在铁路支线的这地方
we'll load the DeLorean onto the tracks here, on the spur
就在这废弃的旧银矿旁
right by the old abandoned silver mine.
这个转换杆可将火车导向支线
The switch track is where the spur runs off the main line
直往下走三里就可到达克雷顿...修那许峡谷
three miles out to Clayton... Shonash Ravine.
火车在星期一早上八点离站
The train leaves the station at 8:00 Monday morning.
我们将在此拦下它 将机关车和煤水车分开
We'll stop it here, uncouple the cars from the tender,
板下转换杆 然后挟持...
throw the switch track, and then we'll hijack...
借用这机关车 用它来推动时光旅行车
Borrow the locomotive and use it to push the time machine.
根据我的计算
According to my calculations,
我们将在抵达峡谷的边缘之前
we'll reach 88 miles per hour
达到每小时88英里的速度
just before we hit the edge of the ravine,
这时候我们就将在一瞬间传送回1985年
at which point we'll be instantaneously transported back to 1985
然后安全地滑过已完成的桥
and coast safely across the completed bridge.
这是什么意思? 不归点
What does this mean? "Point of no return."
那是我们的紧急停止点
That's our fail-safe point.
在到达那里之前 我们都还有足够的时间
Up until there, we have still have enough time
停住火车 以免栽进那峡谷
to stop the locomotive before it plunges into the ravine.
但只要我们一通过这风车
But once we pass this windmill,
就是不成功便成仁
it's the future or bust.
来 马丁 把它接在正极上
Here you go, Marty. Connect that to the positive terminal.
好 马丁 全都准备好了?
All right, Marty, you all set?
都好了 开始!
Yeah. Yeah. Go!
火车由车站开出!
Train pulling out of the station!
慢慢接近那转换点!
Coming up to the switch track!
在转换点停下来!
Stop at the switch track!
转换铁轨!
Throw the switch!
开始推动德罗林车前进!
Pull up to the DeLorean!
将德罗林推到每小时88英里!
Pushing the DeLorean up to 88 miles per hour!
再简单不过了
It couldn't be simpler.
哈啰
Hello.
艾米?
Emmett?
是克蕾拉
It's Clara.
快! 把德罗林车盖起来!
Quick, cover the DeLorean!
哈啰
Hello.
Why, hello.
这可真是个惊喜啊
This is quite a surprise.
希望我没打扰到你们
Well, I hope I'm not disturbing anything.
没有 我们只是在做铁路模型
Oh, no, no, we were just doing a little model railroading.
艾米 当我的行李从马车上掉下来时
Emmett, when my bags were thrown from the wagon,
我的望远镜被碰坏了
my telescope was damaged.
既然你说你对科学很有兴趣
And since you mentioned an interest in science,
我想你应该可以帮我把它修好
I thought you might be able to repair it for me.
当然了 我会付你酬劳的
I would pay you, of course.
我是绝对不会向你收钱的
Oh, no, no, no. I wouldn't think of charging you for this.
让我先看看
Well, let's have a look at it.
我想其中的一个镜片可能偏掉了
I think a lens may be out of alignment,
因为你若是将它往这边转
because if you move it this way,
影像就会变得模糊 看见了没?
the image turns fuzzy. See?
但你若是把它转向另一边...
But if you turn it the other way then...
一切都变得...
Everything becomes...
...非常清楚
...clear.
我可以马上修理 今天晚上就可以还给你
I could repair it right away and have it for you tonight.
今天晚上是这个镇的嘉年华会
Oh, tonight is the town festival.
我不敢奢望你在这么重要的节日
I wouldn't dream of having you work on my telescope
还会有时间修我的望远镜
during such an important occasion.
你们打算参与这盛会 对吧?
You are planning on attending, aren't you?
事实上 小姐 我不认为...
Well, actually, ma'am, I don't think...
是啊 当然了 嘉年华会
Yes, of course, the festival.
既然这样
Well, in that case,
我们今晚就在庆典中碰头了 艾米
I'll see you this evening at the festival, Emmett.
- 伊斯特伍德先生 - 小姐
- Mr. Eastwood. - Ma'am.
谢谢你帮我修我的望远镜
Thank you for taking care of my telescope.
千万别客气
You're quite welcome.
这望远镜真不错
It's a nice telescope.
各位先生女士们
Ladies and gentlemen,
身为山谷市的市长 我很荣幸能在此
as mayor of Hill Valley, it gives me great pleasure
把这座钟献给希尔郡的乡亲们!
to dedicate this clock to the people of Hill County!
愿它能永远地保存下去!
May it stand for all time!
时候到了就告诉我 各位
Tell me when, gentlemen.
三 二 一!
Three! Two! One!
启用!
Now!
开始各种庆祝活动吧!
Let the festivities begin!
你知道吗? 马丁
You know, Marty, in a way, it's fitting
你和我有资格在此见证这一切
that you and I are here to witness this.
可惜我没把照相机带来
It's too bad I didn't bring my camera.
准备好? 两位
Ready, gentlemen?
问题是我们将永远无法把这照片拿给别人看
The only problem is we'll never be able to show it to anybody.
微笑 博士
Smile, Doc.
哈!
Yee-ha!
好棒的音乐!
What great music!
是啊 而且还有节奏 可以跳舞
Yeah, it's got a beat, and you can dance to it.
男士们 快上前来
Step right up gentlemen
试试胆识 在此展示的是
and test your mettle with the latest products
位于康乃迪克州哈特佛的萨穆尔·科尔特上校火器制造厂
from Colonel Samuel Colt's Patent Firearms Manufacturing Company
所推出的最新产品
of Hartford, Connecticut.
现在 就拿这一型来做例子
Now, take this model, for example.
这是经过改良精制的 科尔特转轮手枪
The new, improved and refined Colt Peacemaker
你今晚只要花12块的最低价就能够拥有它
selling to you tonight for the low, low price of $12.
- 晚安 - 晚安
- Good evening. - Evening.
你看来好漂亮
You look very nice.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你是否想...
Would you like...
你是否愿意...
Would you care to...
乐意之至
I'd love to.
年轻人 要不要上来试试?
Young man, how about you? You want to give it a try?
不 不 谢谢你 博士 这...
No, no. No, thanks. Hey, Doc, this...
老弟!
Son!
Sonny boy!
博士会跳舞?
The Doc can dance?
老弟 老弟 老弟
Son. Son. Son!
我刚刚说过连吃奶的娃儿都会用这武器
Hey, I just told you that even a baby could handle this weapon.
你该不会不敢尝试连奶娃儿都能做的事吧?
Surely you're not afraid to try something that a baby could do.
我什么也不怕
Hey, I'm not afraid of nothing.
那就来吧 像个男子汉般地站上去
Come on, then. Let's just step up here like a man.
现在 你只需要把那撞针扳到后面
Now, then what you do is you just ease that hammer back there
然后扣下板机就行了
and squeeze off a round.
不 不对!
No, no, no!
对着前面轻轻地扳下去
Right on out there and be real smooth.
这是正确的方式
That's the way you do it.
听着 我可以再试一次吗?
Listen, can I try that again?
当然可以
Yeah, go ahead.
告诉我
Hey, just tell me one thing.
你这一手好枪法是在哪学的?
Where did you learn to shoot like that?
统一便利商店
7-Eleven.
贝夫 你确定那个铁匠
Buford, you sure that blacksmith
会参加这庆典吗?
is gonna be at this here shindig?
他一定会来 今晚所有的人都会来
Sure he's here. Everybody's here tonight.
各位如果想参加庆典活动
You gentlemen will have to check your firearms
就得将武器寄放在这里
if you want to join in on the festivities.
谁能逼我们缴枪? 你?
Who's gonna make us, tenderfoot? You?
我能
I am.
史屈克兰警长 我不晓得你已回到这镇上了
Marshal Strickland. I didn't know you was back in town.
如果你不识字无法读那告示
If you can't read the sign, Tannen,
我想你应该认识这东西
I presume you can read this.
你这算什么男子汉?
Pretty tough hombre when you're pointing
拿着猎枪对着别人的背后
a scatter gun at a man's back.
和你一样 添南 我会尽一切可能争取到优势
Just like you, Tannen, I take every advantage I can get.
你到底要不要把枪寄放在这里?
Now you gonna check your iron?
我只是跟你的副警长开开玩笑
I was just joking with your deputy.
我当然要寄放我的枪
Of course, I'm gonna check my iron.
我们都打算这么做对吧? 弟兄们
We all were. Weren't we, boys?
是啊
Yeah, right.
添南
Tannen.
还有你的刀子
Your knife, too.
笑一下吧 警长 这毕竟是个欢乐的场合啊
Smile, Marshal. After all, this is a party.
唯一能让我露出笑容的场合
Only party I'll be smiling at
就是当你收到绞刑的那一天
is the one that sees you at the end of a rope.
好好玩吧!
Have fun!
你就是要这样对付他们 儿子
See, that's how you handle them, Son.
永不让步
Never give them an inch
在任何时候都得维持纪律
and maintain discipline at all times.
记住这个字 纪律
Remember that word, discipline.
我会的 爸
I will, Pa.
多谢你
Thank you very much.
是你啊 伊斯特伍德先生 真高兴看见你
Why, Mr. Eastwood, nice to see you.
看来你已经换上较体面的衣服了 再加上一顶好帽了
I see you got yourself some respectable clothes, lad, and a fine hat.
是啊 有些人
Yeah, well, a couple people
不喜欢我戴着另一顶的样子
didn't like the way the other one looked on me.
这顶确实很适合你 伊斯特伍德先生
Sure, and that one suits you, Mr. Eastwood.
- 非常体面 - 谢谢你
- It's very becoming. - Oh, thanks.
是飞盘呢! 正点(好远)
Hey, "Frisbie." Far out.
那是什么意思?
What was the meaning of that?
明明就摆在他的面前
It was right in front of him. Aye.
- 那是我的! - 不再是了
- Hey, that's mine! - Not anymore.
拿给我
Give me that.
他在那里 贝夫
There he is, Buford.
- 哪里? - 那边
- Where? - There.
正在跟那个妞儿跳舞
Dancing with that piece of calico.
你打算怎么做? 老大
THUG: What are you gonna do, boss?
我想 如果我把枪管
I figure if I bury this muzzle
紧紧地抵住他的背 没人会听见枪声
deep enough in his back, nobody will hear the shot.
小心点 贝夫 它只有一颗子弹
Careful, Buford. You ain't got but one bullet with that.
我只要一颗就足够了
I only need one.
我告诉过你背后要长眼睛 铁匠
I told you to watch your back, smithy.
添南 你来早了
Tannen, you're early.
这是一把掌心雷 铁匠 虽小却够威力
It's a Derringer, smithy. Small but effective.
上回被我用这把枪打中的家伙 整整两天后才死
The last time I used it, fellow took two whole days to die.
体内大量出血
Bled to death inside.
死得非常痛苦
It was real, real painful.
这表示你会在星期一的晚饭时间魂归西天
That means you'll be dead by about supper time Monday.
对不起 我不知道你以为你是谁 但我们正在跳舞
Excuse me. I don't know who you think you are, but we're dancing.
看看我们遇上了谁?
Well, look at what we have here.
不为我介绍一下这女士?
Ain't you gonna introduce me to the lady?
我想跳支舞
I'd like a dance.
你休想
I wouldn't give you the pleasure.
你还是开枪好了
You'll just have to go ahead and shoot.
好吧
All right.
不! 艾米 我跟他跳好了
No, no. Emmett, I'll dance with him.
弟兄们 好好陪这位铁匠
Boys, keep the blacksmith company
让我跟这位姑娘认识一下!
while I get acquainted with the filly!
当我的舞伴手里有把枪时 我无法跳得很好
I don't dance very well when my partner has a gun in his hand.
你会适应的 你会适应的
You'll learn. You'll learn.
铁匠 我看我就从她身上讨回那八十块吧!
You know, smithy, maybe I'll just take my $80 worth out of her!
添南 放开她!
Tannen, leave her alone!
是啊 我敢说你一定能做些值八十块的事
Yeah, I bet there's something you can do that's worth $80.
我想你是低估我了 先生
I believe you've underestimated me, mister.
是吗?
Have I?
- 放开我! 住手! 住手 - 你该死! 添南!
- Stop it! - Damn you, Tannen!
不 该死的是你
No, I damn you!
我要送你下地狱去
I damn you to hell!
你
You.
少找他麻烦! 混蛋
Hey, lighten up, jerk!
好大的口气! 小鬼
Mighty strong words, runt!
你敢用盘子以外的东西
You man enough to back them up
替他们出头吗?
with more than just a pie plate?
听着 别烦我的朋友们就行了
Look, just leave my friends alone.
怎么? 小子 你没胆吗?
What's wrong, dude? You yellow?
我就知道 是个胆小鬼
That's what I thought. A yellow belly.
我不是胆小鬼
Nobody calls me yellow.
我们现在就来做个了断吧
Then let's finish it right now.
现在不行 贝夫 警长把我们的枪收走了
Not now, Buford. Marshal's got our guns.
好 我们就明天做个了断!
Like I said, we'll finish this tomorrow!
明天我们要去抢松树镇的驿马车
Tomorrow we're robbing the Pine City stage.
星期一呢? 我们星期一有节目吗?
What about Monday? We doing anything Monday?
没有 星期一可以 你可以星期一杀他
No, Monday would be fine. You can kill him on Monday.
我星期一会回这里来
I'll be back this way on Monday.
我们到时再算这笔帐
We'll settle this then.
就在那边的大街上
Right there out in the street
皇宫酒馆的前面
in front of the Palace Saloon.
好吧 什么时候?
Yeah, right. When?
- 日正当中? - 中午?
- High noon? - Noon?
我一向都在吃早餐前杀人的 七点钟!
I do my killing before breakfast. 7:00!
八点好了 我一向都吃过早餐才杀人
8:00. I do my killing after breakfast.
马丁!
Marty!
好了 你们两个住手
All right, now. Break it up.
这是怎么回事?
What's all this about?
你又在这里惹麻烦了? 添南
You causing trouble here, Tannen?
没惹麻烦 警长
No trouble, Marshal.
只是我跟伊斯特伍德之间的私事
Just a little personal matter between me and Eastwood.
和法律无关
This don't concern the law.
今晚所有的事都和法律有关 好了 大家散开
Tonight, everything concerns the law. Now break it up.
若有任何人闹事 都得在郡立监狱里待上十五天
Any brawling, it's 15 days in the county jail.
好了 各位 这是个派对
All right, folks. Come on, this is a party.
来吧 大伙儿好好乐一下!
Come on! Let's have some fun!
星期一早上8点 小鬼
8:00 Monday, runt.
如果你不出现
If you ain't here,
我就是走遍天涯海角也要找到你 把你当鸭子宰了
I'll hunt you and shoot you down like a duck.
是狗 贝夫 像杀狗般地把他宰了
It's "dog," Buford. Shoot him down like a dog.
我们走! 弟兄们 让这些娘娘腔的享受他们的派对!
Let's go, boys! Let these sissies have their party!
马丁 你在干么
Marty, what are you doing,
你答应跟添南决斗?
saying you're gonna meet Tannen?
博士 你放心好了
Hey, Doc, Doc, don't worry about it.
星期一早上8点
Monday morning 8:00 a.m.
我们早就走了 不是吗?
We're gonna be gone, right?
没错 但火车若是误点呢?
Theoretically, yes, but what if the train's late?
误点? 我们待会再谈这件事
Late? We'll discuss this later.
不 现在就谈 误点? 什么意思?
No, we'll discuss it now. Late? What do you mean?
谢谢你英勇的行为 伊斯特伍德先生
Thank you for your gallantry, Mr. Eastwood.
别客气
Hey, ma'am.
如果你没及时插手 艾米可能会挨枪的
Had you not interceded, Emmett might have been shot.
马丁...克林特 我要送克蕾拉回去
Marty... Clint, I'm gonna take Clara home.
好的 晚安 博士 晚安 克蕾拉
Right. Good night, Doc. Good night, Clara.
你可教训了他 伊斯特伍德先生
You sure set him straight, Mr. Eastwood.
我真高兴终于有人有勇气
I'm glad somebody finally got the gumption
站出来对抗那个狗杂种
to stand up to that son of a bitch.
你真是了不起 伊斯特伍德先生
You're all right in my book, Mr. Eastwood.
我请你喝一杯
I'd like to buy you a drink.
听着 我不想喝酒
Hey, listen, I don't want a drink.
不必买给我任何东西 年轻人
You don't have to buy me anything. Young man. Young man.
- 这算不了什么 - 我要你收下这把全新的
- It was no big deal. - I'd like for you to have this brand-new
科尔特枪 免费送给你
Colt Peacemaker and gun belt free of charge.
免费?
Free?
我要让每个人知道
I want everybody to know
那把杀死贝夫·添南的枪 是一把科尔特的枪!
that the gun that shot Buford Tannen was a Colt Peacemaker!
没问题 多谢你了
Hey, no problem. Thanks a lot.
当然 你应该也知道
Of course you understand
如果你输了 我就要将它收回
that if you lose, I'm taking it back.
多谢你了
Thanks again.
你跟他正面冲突 伊斯特伍德先生
You had him, Mr. Eastwood.
你大可走开
You could have just walked away,
没有人会怪你的
and nobody would have thought the less of you for it.
大不了被人在背后说两句 或是被贝夫嘲笑几次
All it would have been was words, hot air from a buffoon.
但你却让他邀你决斗
Instead, you let him rile you.
让他引诱你用他的规则来解决纷争
Rile you into playing his game, his way, by his rules.
谢穆斯 别紧张 我知道自己在做什么
Seamus, relax. I know what I'm doing.
他让我想起可怜的马丁
He reminds me of poor Martin.
是啊
Aye.
- 谁? - 我弟弟
- Who? - Me brother.
慢着
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
你的弟弟叫马丁·麦佛莱?
You have a brother named Martin McFly?
是我的亡弟
Had a brother.
马丁在世时老爱与人决斗
Martin used to let men provoke him into fighting.
他总认为如果他拒绝的话 人家会认为他没胆
He was concerned that people would think him a coward if he refused.
结果他才会在维吉尼亚城
That's how he got a Bowie knife shoved through his belly
被人在肚子上刺了一刀
in a saloon in Virginia City.
从不考虑未来 可怜的马丁
Never considered the future, poor Martin.
愿他的灵魂安息
God rest his soul.
我希望你能多为未来着想 伊斯特伍德先生
Sure, and I hope you're considering the future, Mr. Eastwood.
我无时无刻不在想未来
I think about it all the time.
还有西北方中央的那巨蟹座
And that crater in the middle north west,
那个孤单的 像一团星爆似的...
the one that's out there all by itself like a starburst...
...那颗叫做哥白尼
...that one's called Copernicus.
你听我这口吻 我觉得自己像在教书似的
Listen to me. I feel like I'm teaching school.
不 拜托 请继续教下去
Please, continue the lesson.
我不晓得天文学是如此的有趣
I never found lunar geography so fascinating.
你真是博学多闻
You're quite knowledgeable.
当我十一岁时 我得了白喉病
When I was 11, I had diphtheria.
被隔离了三个月
I was quarantined for three months.
我父亲买了这个望远镜
So my father brought this telescope,
把它放在我的床边
and he put it next to my bed
让我能看到窗外的风景
so I could see everything out the window.
艾米 你想我们将来是否能像搭火车横越这个国家般地
Emmett, do you think we'll ever be able to travel to the moon
到月球上去旅行?
the way we travel across the country on trains?
绝对可能 只不过还得再等上84年的时间 也不是搭火车去
Definitely. Although not for 84 years and not on trains.
我们将会有太空船 利用火箭的推力升空
We'll have space vehicles, capsules sent aloft with rockets.
某种能产生猛烈爆炸的装置
Devices that create giant explosions.
那爆炸的威力之强大...
Explosions so powerful that they just...
足以脱离地心引力的控制
That they break the pull of the Earth's gravity
将那飞行器送到外太空去
and send the projectile through outer space.
艾米 我也读过那本书啊!
Emmett, I read that book, too!
你是在引述儒勒·凡尔纳
You're quoting Jules Verne
在《月球之旅》里所描述的
From the Earth to the Moon.
你也读儒勒·凡尔纳的书?
You've read Jules Verne?
我最喜欢儒勒·凡尔纳的书
I adore Jules Verne.
我也是
So do I.
那部《海底两万里》是我最喜欢的
Twenty Thousand Leagues Under the Sea. My absolute favorite.
当我小时候第一次读这本书时
The first time I read that when I was a little boy,
我就好想认识尼莫船长
why, I wanted to meet Captain Nemo.
别开玩笑了 艾米
Don't tease, Emmett.
你不可能在小时候读过那本书的
You couldn't have read that when you were a boy.
它是十年前才出版的啊
It was only first published 10 years ago.
是啊 我是说 它让我觉得自己像个小男孩
Oh, yes. Well, I meant it made me feel like a boy.
我这辈子还不曾遇见过一个喜欢儒勒·凡尔纳的书的女性
I never met a woman who liked Jules Verne before.
我这辈子也不曾遇见过一个像你这样的男人
I never ever met a man like you before.
博士?
Doc?
我希望你知道自己在做什么
Hope you know what you're doing.
你在跟我说话?
You talking to me?
你在跟我说话? 添南
You talking to me, Tannen?
这里只有我一个人
Well, I'm the only one here.
来吧! 不怕死就来
Go ahead, make my day.
早 伊斯特伍德先生
Say good morning, Mr. Eastwood.
早
Morning.
抽根雪茄吧 伊斯特伍德先生
Have a cigar, Mr. Eastwood.
今天需要我效劳吗? 伊斯特伍德先生
Anything I can do for you today, Mr. Eastwood?
不 不用了
No, that's fine.
祝你明天好运 伊斯特伍德先生
Good luck tomorrow, Mr. Eastwood.
我们会为你祈祷
We'll be praying for you.
谢了
Thanks.
早 伊斯特伍德先生
Good morning, Mr. Eastwood.
明天打算穿新衣服上场吗?
Interest you in a new suit for tomorrow?
不用了 谢谢你
I'm fine. Thanks.
博士 你在干什么啊?
Doc, what are you doing?
没什么
Oh, nothing.
我只是出来呼吸一下清晨的空气
I was just out enjoying the morning air.
此地的早晨美极了 你说是不是?
It's really lovely here in the morning. Don't you think?
对 美极了 博土
Yeah, it's lovely, Doc.
听着 我们把德罗林车放上铁轨
So listen, we've got to load the DeLorean up
准备上路吧 好吗?
and get ready to roll, all right?
看 是墓碑呢
Hey, look at that, the tombstone.
马丁 再让我看看那张照片
Marty, let me see that photograph again.
我的名字 已经消失了
My name, it's vanished.
这真是太好了 博士 你还不明白吗?
Hey, that's great, Doc. Don't you get it?
我们明天就要回未来去了
We're going back to the future tomorrow,
这一切都将改变
so everything's being erased.
但只有我的名字消失
But only my name is erased.
这块墓碑和上面的日期仍然存在
The tombstone itself and the date still remain.
这是说不通的
That doesn't make sense.
我们知道这张照片代表着
We know that this photograph represents what will happen
今天的事件若是延续到明天
if the events of today continue
则将会发生的事
to run their course into tomorrow.
没错 那又怎样?
Right. So?
对不起 伊斯特伍德先生
Excuse me, Mr. Eastwood.
我要量你的身材
I just need to take your measurements.
听着 兄弟 我不想买西装
Oh, look, pal, I don't want to buy a suit.
不 我是在量你棺材的尺寸
No, this is for your coffin.
我的棺材?
My coffin?
你的赔率是2比1
Well, the odds are running two to one against you.
趁早准备也好
Might as well be prepared.
所以 刻在那块墓碑上的可能不是我的名字
So it may not be my name that's supposed to end up on this tombstone.
可能是你的
It may be yours.
我的天
Great Scott.
我知道 这恐怕难以承受
I know. This is heavy.
马丁 你带着那把枪做什么?
Marty, why are you wearing that gun?
你该不会真的打算明天和添南决斗吧?
You're not considering going up against Tannen tomorrow?
博士 明天一大早我将和你回到未来
Doc, tomorrow morning I'm going back to the future with you.
但贝夫·添南若是来找麻烦的话
But if Buford Tannen comes looking for trouble,
我将会要他好看
I'm gonna be ready for him.
你也听见那混蛋昨晚用什么字眼骂我
You heard what that son of a bitch called me last night.
马丁 你不能每回一有人骂你
Marty, you can't go losing your judgment
你就失去理智
every time someone calls you a name.
你将来就是因为这样
That's exactly what causes you
而才出事的
to get into that accident in the future.
我将来会发生什么事?
What? What about my future?
我不能告诉你 这可能会让事情变得更糟
I can't tell you. It might make things worse.
慢着 博士 我在未来出了什么事?
Wait a minute. Doc, what is wrong with my future?
马丁 我们都得做一些
Marty, we all have to make decisions
会改变我们一生的决定
that affect the course of our lives.
你得做你应该做的事
You've got to do what you've got to do,
我也得做我应该做的事
and I've got to do what I've got to do.
- 马丁 - 什么事?
- Marty. - Yeah.
我已经做了决定
I've made a decision. Uh-huh.
我明天不跟你回去了
I'm not going with you tomorrow.
我要留在这里
I'm staying here.
你在胡说什么啊? 博士
What are you talking about, Doc?
我没必要否认这事实
There's no point in denying it.
我爱上克蕾拉了
I'm in love with Clara.
我的天
Oh, man.
博士 我们不属于这里啊 我们两个都不属于这里
Doc, we don't belong here. Neither one of us.
你知道吗? 明天被杀的人仍有可能是你
You know, it could still be you that gets shot tomorrow.
这块墓碑仍有可能是你的未来
This tombstone could still be in your future.
马丁 未来不是一成不变的
Marty, the future isn't written.
它可以被改变 这点你也知道
It can be changed. You know that.
任何人都可以把他们的未来改变成他们所喜欢的样子
Anyone can make their future whatever they want it to be.
我不能让这张小小的照片
I can't let this one little photograph
决定我的一辈子
determine my entire destiny.
我得依照
I have to live my life
我内心认为正确的方式 来过我的生活
according to what I believe is right in my heart.
博士 你是个科学家啊
Doc, you're a scientist.
你倒是说说看 你脑袋所认为该做的事是什么?
So you tell me. What's the right thing to do up here?
你说得对 马丁
You're right, Marty.
这玩意真管用
Wow, that worked great.
我最起码得跟她说声再见
I've at least got to tell her goodbye.
别这样 博士 想想看
Come on, Doc. Think about it.
你该怎么告诉她?
What are you gonna say to her?
"我得回到未来去? "
"I've got to go back to the future?"
我是说 她是不会了解的 博士
I mean, she's not gonna understand that, Doc.
连和你在一起的我
Hell, I'm in it with you,
都不怎么了解
and I don't even understand it.
博士 听我说
Doc, listen.
或许我们可以...
Maybe we...
或许我们可以带克蕾拉一起走
I don't know, maybe we can just take Clara with us.
回到未来去?
To the future?
你刚刚提醒过我 马丁 我是个科学家
As you reminded me, Marty, I'm a scientist,
我得以科学的角度来看这件事
so I must be scientific about this.
我曾经警告过你不可为了私益
I cautioned you about disrupting the continuum
而破坏了时空的连续性
for your own personal benefit.
所以我自己也不能这么做
Therefore, I must do no less.
我们将照计划进行
We shall proceed as planned,
而在我们一回到1985年后
and as soon as we return to 1985,
我们就把这不祥的机器毁掉
we'll destroy this infernal machine.
时光旅行太让人痛苦了
Traveling through time has become much too painful.
是我 艾米 克蕾拉
It's Emmett, Clara.
艾米 你不进来吗?
Emmett, won't you come in?
不 我想还是不要...
No, I better not. I...
怎么回事?
What's wrong?
我是来道别的
I've come to say goodbye.
道别? 你要上哪去?
Goodbye? Well, where are you going?
我要走了
I'm going away.
我恐怕再也见不到你了
And well, I'm afraid I'll never see you again.
艾米!
Emmett!
克蕾拉 我要你知道我非常爱你
Clara, I want you to know that I care about you deeply.
但我明白我是不属于这里的
But I've realized that I don't belong here,
我得回到我所来的地方去
and I have to go back where I came from.
那是什么地方?
And where might that be?
我不能告诉你
I can't tell you.
不管你要去哪 带我一起走
Well, wherever you're going, take me with you.
我不能这么做 克蕾拉
I can't, Clara.
我只希望一切能不演变至此
I wish it didn't have to be this way,
但请你相信我
but just believe me when I tell you
我这辈子永远不会忘记你 而且 我永远爱着你
that I'll never forget you and that I love you.
我不明白你想告诉我什么
I don't understand what you're trying to say.
克蕾拉 我不认为你能够了解这件事
Clara, I don't think there's any way that you can understand it.
求求你 艾米 我一定得知道
Please, Emmett. Please, I have to know.
如果你真的爱我的话
If you sincerely do love me,
那就把实情告诉我
then tell me the truth.
好吧
All right then.
我是由未来回来的
I'm from the future.
我乘坐一架我所发明的时光机器回到这个时代
I came here in a time machine that I invented,
明天 我就得回到1985年
and tomorrow I have to go back to the year 1985.
是的 艾米
Yes, Emmett.
我很能够了解
I do understand.
我明白 因为你知道
I understand that because you know
我喜爱儒勒·凡尔纳所写的书
I'm partial to the writings of Jules Verne,
你编造出这种谎言
you concocted those mendacities
想骗我上当
in order to take advantage of me.
我这辈子领教过许多谎言
Oh! I've heard some whoppers in my day,
但你要我相信你这些鬼话
but the fact that you'd expect me
简直是对我的一大侮辱
to entertain a notion like that
可耻之至!
is so insulting and degrading!
你只需要说 "我不爱你
All you had to say is, "I don't love you,
我不想再见到你"
and I don't want to see you anymore."
这对我起码还比较尊重!
That, at least, would have been respectful!
但事实并不是这样啊
But that's not the truth.
见到你真好
Good to see you, too.
艾米 要杯和往常一样的?
Emmett. What can I get you? The usual?
不 切斯特 我今晚需要
No, Chester, I'm gonna need something
烈一点的东西
a lot stronger than that tonight.
沙士?
Sarsaparilla.
给我威士忌 却斯特
Whiskey, Chester.
威士忌? 艾米 你确定吗?
Whiskey? Emmett, are you sure?
还记得你国庆日那天发生的事?
You know what happened to you on the Fourth of July.
给我威士忌
Whiskey.
好吧 反正我又不是你爸爸
Okay, I ain't your papa.
我只是不希望看到你做傻事
Just don't want to see you do the wrong thing.
整瓶放在这里
You can leave the bottle.
是为了女人 对不对?
It's a woman, right?
我就知道 我走遍了全国各地
I knew it. I have seen that look on a man's face
在上千个男人脸上见过这表情
a thousand times all across the country.
我只能告诉你 朋友 你会忘了她的
All I can tell you, friend, is you'll get over her.
不可能 克蕾拉这样的女人 百万中才有一个
Oh... Clara was one in a million.
十亿中才有一个 是恒河里的一粒沙了
One in a billion. One in a googolplex.
我梦中的女人 而我却永远的失去了她
The woman of my dreams, and I've lost her for all time.
我可以向你保证 先生 你还会碰到别的女人的
I can assure you, sir, there are other women.
根据我在全国各地推销这铁丝网所得到的经验
Why, peddling this barbed wire all across the country
让我知道一件事
has taught me one thing for certain,
那就是你永远无法知道未来将会怎样
is that you never know what the future might bring.
未来 我可以告诉你未来将会怎样
The future. Oh, I can tell you about the future.
老天 我睡得像个死人似的
Oh, man, did I sleep.
几点了? 博士
What time is it, Doc?
博士?
Doc?
醒醒!
Wake up!
起来! 我们该上路了!
Get up! Let's go!
我还得赶去杀那臭小子
I got me a runt to kill.
时间还早啊! 老大 你急什么?
It's still early, boss. What's your hurry?
我饿了
I'm hungry.
而且在未来 我们将不需要马
And in the future, we don't need horses.
我们将使用名叫汽车的动力车辆
We have motorized carriages called automobiles.
如果每个人都有辆这种叫做汽什么的鸟玩意
If everybody's got one of these auto whatsits,
人们还会走路或跑步吗?
does anybody walk or run anymore?
当然会跑步了 但是为了休闲 为了娱乐
Of course we run, but for recreation, for fun.
拿跑步当做娱乐? 这算哪门子的娱乐啊?
Run for fun? What the hell kind of fun is that?
博士 博士!
Doc! Doc!
他已经喝几杯了?
How much has he had?
一杯也没有 那还是第一杯
None. That's the first one,
他甚至连第一杯都还没下肚
and he hasn't touched it yet.
他只喜欢捧着那杯酒
He just likes to hold it.
博士! 博士 你在干么啊?
Doc! Doc! What are you doing?
我失去她了 马丁 此地对我已不值得留恋了
I've lost her, Marty. There's nothing left for me here.
好 所以你便得跟我回去
All right, that's why you gotta come back with me.
回哪去?
Where?
回到未来啊!
Back to the future!
对! 我们上路吧!
Right! Let's get going!
好极了
Great.
各位 失陪了 我的小友和我还得赶搭一班火车
Gentlemen, excuse me, but my friend and I have to catch a train.
我敬你 铁匠
Here's to you, blacksmith.
敬未来一杯
And to the future.
阿门
Amen.
- 阿门 - 不!
- Amen. - Emmett, no!
博士 博士 博士!
Doc! Doc! Doc!
快点 博士 醒醒 快醒醒 博士!
Come on, Doc. Wake up. Wake up, Doc!
他喝几杯了?
How many did he have?
就那一杯
Just the one.
只有一杯? 别装醉了 博土
Just the one? Come on, Doc.
有的人的酒量就是这么差
There's a fellow that can't hold his liquor.
帮我弄些黑咖啡来!
Get me some coffee. Black!
乔伊 拿咖啡来!
Joey, coffee!
小姐?
Ma'am?
八点的火车最远到哪里?
How far does the 8:00 train go?
终点站是旧金山
San Francisco is the end of the line.
给我一张单程票
I'll take a one-way ticket.
如果你要立刻把他弄醒 老弟
You want to sober him up in a hurry, son,
你就得用些比咖啡更够劲的东西
you're gonna have to use something a lot stronger than coffee.
你建议用什么?
Yeah, what do you suggest?
乔伊 我们来做些醒酒剂
Joey, let's make some wake-up juice.
来吧 博士 喝下去
Come on, Doc, swallow. Here we go.
十分钟后
In about 10 minutes,
他将有如星期天的牧师般地清醒
he's gonna be as sober as a priest on Sunday.
十分钟?
Ten minutes!
我们为什么总在最后关头出事?
Why do we have to cut these things so damn close?
来 用这衣夹夹住他的鼻子
Here, stick this clothespin on his nose.
当他把嘴巴张开
When he opens up his mouth,
就把这玩意儿灌进他的嘴里
go ahead and pour it on down his gullet.
对了 往后退一点
Oh, and stand back.
他还没醒过来!
He's still out!
刚刚那只是反射作用罢了
Oh, that? That was just a reflex action.
还得再等几分钟
It's gonna take a few more minutes
这东西才能让他的脑袋完全清醒
for the stuff to really clear up his head.
真是太好了
Perfect.
快点 博士 快醒醒
Come on, Doc. Come on, wake up, buddy.
快醒醒 博士
Wake up, Doc! Come on. Come on.
谢穆斯 我没料到你今天早上会来
Seamus, wouldn't expect to see you here this morning.
是啊 但我心里有个声音叫我一定得来
Aye. Something inside me told me I should be here
就好像这关系着我的未来似的
as if my future had something to do with it.
他马上就会醒过来了
He'll come around in a minute. Come on.
醒醒 快醒醒 博土!
Come on, Doc. Let's go, Doc!
醒醒啊! 博士 醒醒
Let's wake up now, buddy. Come on.
你在里面吗? 伊斯特伍德
Are you in there, Eastwood?
已经八点了! 我叫你给我出来
It's 8:00, and I'm calling you out.
还不到八点钟啊!
It's not 8:00 yet!
以我的表为准!
It is by my watch!
我们来了断这笔帐! 臭小子!
Let's settle this once and for all, runt!
难道你是没胆吗?
Or ain't you got the gumption?
(克林特·伊斯特伍德长眠于此)
听着
Listen.
我今天觉得手不大顺
I'm not really feeling up to this today.
所以我只好弃权
So I'm gonna have to forfeit.
弃权?
Forfeit?
这是什么意思?
What's that mean?
意思是你不必决斗就赢了
It means that you win without a fight.
不必开枪? 他不能这么做啊
Without shooting? He can't do that.
你不能这么做啊!
Hey, you can't do that!
你知道我的看法是如何吗?
You know what I think?
我认为你是个没用的胆小鬼!
I think you ain't nothing but a gutless, yellow turd!
我给你数到十的时间
And I'm giving you to the count of 10
到外面来证明我错了!
to come out here and prove I'm wrong!
一!
One!
博士 快点 醒醒 兄弟
Doc, come on, sober up, buddy. Let's go. Come on.
二!
Two!
你还是快出去吧 老弟
You better get out there, son.
我押了20块的金子赌你获胜 别让我失望了
I got $20 gold bet on you, so don't let me down.
三!
Three!
我押了30块的金子赌你输 你更不能让我失望
I got $30 gold bet against you, so don't let me down.
四!
Four!
你还是面对现实吧 老弟
You better face up to it, son,
因为你若是不出去的话...
because if you don't go out there...
怎样? 五!
What? Five!
如果我不出去呢?
What if I don't go out there?
你就是个懦夫
You're a coward.
六!
Six!
你这辈子都将被贴上懦夫的标签!
And you'll be branded a coward for the rest of your days!
不管你以后走到哪里 大家都会说克林特·伊斯特伍德
Everybody everywhere will say Clint Eastwood
是西部最可耻的弱夫!
is the biggest yellow belly in the West!
七!
Seven!
这个!
Here!
八!
Eight!
我已经有枪了
I already got a gun.
九!
Nine!
十!
Ten!
你听见了没? 臭小子
Do you hear me, runt?
我已经数到了10了 你这个没胆没用的懦夫!
I said that's 10, you gutless, yellow pie-slinger!
他根本是个王八蛋!
He's an asshole!
我才不在乎添南说什么!
I don't care what Tannen says!
我也不在乎别人说什么
And I don't care what anybody else says either.
博士! 博士 你没事吧?
Doc! Doc, you okay?
我想是吧
I think so.
我的头痛死了!
What a headache!
听着 你这地方有后门吗?
Listen, you got a back door to this place?
有 就在后面
Yeah, it's in the back.
我们走 博士
Let's go, Doc.
你是要出来呢 还是要我进去找你?
Are you coming out here, or do I have to come in after you?
他们这里唯一缺的就是头痛药
The thing I really miss here is Tylenol.
嘿!
Hey!
还想跑? 铁匠!
Reach, blacksmith!
是的 先生 我昨晚遇见那个可怜的家伙
Yes, sir, that poor fellow last night
是我这辈子见过最伤心的人
had the worst case of broken heart I have ever seen.
特别是当他提到
When he said he didn't know
在他伤透了那女孩的心之后
how he could live the rest of his life
他不晓得自己还能如何活下去
knowing how much hurt he'd caused that little girl.
我真的很同情他 衷心地同情他
Well, I really felt for him. I did. Right here.
给我听着! 姓伊斯特伍德的!
Listen up, Eastwood!
老子今天非得宰一个人不可
I aim to shoot somebody today,
但最好是你
and I prefer it'd be you.
但你若是太没种的话
But if you're just too damn yellow,
那我只好宰你这个铁匠朋友了
I guess it'll just have to be your blacksmith friend.
别管我! 马丁 你快逃命!
Forget about me, Marty, and save yourself!
我给你一分钟的时间作决定
You got one minute to decide.
你听见了没? 小子 一分钟!
You hear me, runt? One minute!
我从没见过男人会为了一个女人而如此伤心
I've never seen a man so broken up over a woman.
他说她叫什么名字? 卡拉? 莎拉?
What did he say her name was? Cara? Sara?
- 是克蕾拉 - 对
- Clara. - Clara.
- 对不起 - 什么事? 小姐
- Excuse me. - Ma'am?
这个人是否个子高高的 有着一双大大的像狗般的棕眼
But was this man tall with great big, brown puppy-dog eyes
以及长长的 银白色的直发?
and long silvery, flowing hair?
你认识他啊?
You know him.
艾米!
Emmett!
时间到了 臭小子!
Time's up, runt!
准备上西天吧 铁匠
Prepare to meet your maker, blacksmith.
我就在这里! 添南!
Right here, Tannen!
拔枪吧!
Draw!
不!
No!
我认为我们可以用男子汉的方式来解决此事
I thought we could settle this like men.
你错了 小子
You thought wrong, dude.
谢谢各位
Thank you.
打得好
That was good.
(堆肥)
- 你们知道吗? - 什么?
- You know what I think? - No.
我想贝夫得坐牢了
I think Buford's going to jail.
是啊
Yeah.
把他从那里面拖出来
Get him out of that shit.
去追他们!
Get them!
贝夫·添南 我以
Buford Tannen, you're under arrest
抢劫松树镇驿马车的罪名逮捕你
for robbing the Pine City stage.
你有什么话要说吗?
You got anything to say?
我恨堆肥
I hate manure.
看!
Look!
太好了!
Yes!
火车!
The train!
我们来得及吗?
Can we make it?
我们得走郊狼山路拦截他们
We'll have to cut them off at Coyote Pass.
先生 伊斯特伍德先生
Hey! Hey, mister. Mr. Eastwood.
这是你的枪 先生
Here's your gun, mister.
谢了 小弟
Thanks, kid.
谢穆斯!
Seamus!
它值12块 而且不曾使用过
It's worth $12. Never been used.
或许我会拿它去换顶新帽子
Maybe I'll trade it for a new hat.
好 记着好好照顾那孩子!
Right, and take care of that baby!
我会的!
I will!
艾米!
Emmett!
"时光旅行机器"
"Time machine."
跳!
Come on, Marty!
快 博士
Go, Doc.
快 把手伸给我!
Come on. Give me your hand!
快啊! 马丁
Come on, Marty.
快 我们上!
Come on. Let's go!
蒙上面罩
Masks on.
别动!
Reach!
这是抢劫吗?
Is this a holdup?
不 是个科学实验
It's a science experiment.
在到达前面的转换点之前 把火车停下来
Stop the train just before you hit the switch track up ahead.
博士!
Doc!
把煤水车和机关车分开!
Uncouple the cars from the tender!
我这辈子一直都想这么做
I've wanted to do that all my life.
这些东西是什么?
What are these things, anyway?
是我土法制造的助燃剂
My own version of Pres-to-Logs.
将木料和无烟煤屑压缩在一起
Compressed wood with anthracite dust
再加以化学处理 能让火头烧得更热 更持久
chemically treated to burn hotter and longer.
我平常打铁时都用这个 可以省不少时间
I use them in my forge so I don't have to stoke it.
这三个助燃剂将依次点燃
These three in the furnace will ignite sequentially,
让火烧得更旺
make the fire burn hotter,
增加蒸汽锅炉的功力
kick up the boiler pressure,
让火车跑得更快
and make the train go faster.
一切就绪了!
Ready to roll!
艾米!
Emmett!
马丁 时光旅行仪启动了吗?
Marty, are the time circuits on?
启动 博士!
Check, Doc!
将目的地的时间输入
Input the destination time.
1985年10月27号 早上11点
October 27, 1985, 11:00 a.m.
输入完毕! 好 我们现在以固定的每小时25英里前进 博士
Check. Okay, we're cruising at a steady 25 miles an hour, Doc.
我要把助燃剂丢进锅炉了
I'm throwing in the Pres-to-Logs.
马丁 放在车上的新计速表
Marty, the new gauge on the dashboard
将告诉我们锅炉的温度是多少
will tell us the boiler temperature.
它以三种颜色显示三个助燃剂的点火时间
It's color-coded to indicate when each log will fire.
分别是绿 黄和红三种颜色
Green, yellow and red.
每点燃一个时
Each detonation will be accompanied
火车将会突然加速向前
by a sudden burst of acceleration.
希望我们能在指标达到两千之前
Hopefully, we'll hit 88 miles per hour
就加速到每小时88英里
before the needle gets much past 2,000.
为什么? 超过两千后会怎样?
Why? What happens after it hits 2,000?
整个锅炉将会爆炸!
The whole boiler explodes!
真是太好了!
Perfect!
博士 我们加速到35里了!
Hey, Doc! We just hit 35!
好 马丁 我要过去了!
Okay, Marty. I'm coming aboard!
艾米!
Emmett!
快啊! 快啊!
Come on. Come on.
你最好抓紧点 博士!
You better hold onto something, Doc!
黄色的那个就要点爆了!
The yellow log is about to blow!
我的天
Golly.
我们刚刚超过40里 博士!
We just passed 40, Doc!
艾米!
Emmett!
我们刚超过45里 博士 加油!
We just passed 45, Doc! Go for it!
50里
Fifty.
艾米!
Emmett!
克蕾拉!
Clara!
我爱你!
I love you!
博士! 博士 是怎么回事?
Doc! Doc! What's happening?
是克蕾拉 她在车上!
It's Clara! She's on the train!
克蕾拉? 这下可好了
Clara? Perfect.
她在车上 我要回去接她!
She's in the cab! I'm going back for her!
风车!
The windmill!
博士! 风车 我们已经超过50了 你来不及的!
Doc! The windmill! We're going past 50! You'll never make it!
那我们只好带她一起回去了!
Then we'll have to take her back with us!
继续向我回报速度!
Keep calling out the speed!
克蕾拉 爬到我这边来!
Clara, climb out here to me!
我不知道我是否办得到!
I don't know if I can!
你办得到!
You can do it!
别往下看就行了!
Just don't look down!
这就对了!
That's it!
每小时60英里 博士!
Sixty miles an hour, Doc!
你做得很好 稳稳地走过来!
You're doing fine! Nice and steady!
来啊!
Come on!
再往前一点就行了!
Just a little further!
我办不到 艾米 我害怕!
I can't, Emmett! I'm scared!
70里!
Seventy!
继续往前走 克蕾拉!
Keep coming, Clara!
来啊 来啊! 你做得很好!
Come on! Come on! You're doing fine!
来啊! 放轻松!
Come on! Nice and easy!
别往下看 这就对了 你做得很好!
Don't look down! That's it! You're doing fine!
博士! 红色的那个要点爆了!
Doc! The red log is about to blow!
克蕾拉!
Clara!
艾米!
Emmett!
我试着要抓住你啊!
I'm trying to reach you!
克蕾拉 别松手!
Clara, hold on!
我不行!
I can't!
博士 我把飞行滑板传过去给你!
Doc, I'm gonna slip you the Hoverboard!
马丁 当心!
Marty, watch out!
艾米! 救我!
Emmett, help!
支持住! 克蕾拉!
Hold on, Clara!
博士! 准备好! 博土
Doc, ready, Doc?
接住!
Catch it!
对! 对!
Yes! Yes!
(铁轨尽头)
艾米!
Emmett!
撑住!
Hold on!
太好了!
Yes!
(伊斯特伍德峡谷)
博士
Well, Doc,
它已经被毁掉了
it's destroyed.
正如你所希望的
Just like you wanted.
臭小子 给我...
Hey, butthead, get away...
讲话小心点! 贝夫!
Watch it, Biff!
马丁! 我不是有意要吓你
Marty, I didn't mean to scare you.
只是你穿着这身衣服我认不出来
I didn't recognize you in those clothes.
你在做什么?
What the hell are you doing?
我在给你的车打第二层蜡
Just putting on the second coat now.
你在扮牛仔 是吧?
You going cowboy, huh?
快点 大伙儿 我们快来不及吃早午餐了
Come on, guys. We're gonna be late for brunch.
来了 戴夫
Coming, Dave.
快点! 爸 他们不会替我们
Come on, Dad, we're not gonna hold
留桌子留一整天
your reservations all day.
我找不到我另一副眼镜
I can't find my glasses.
洛莲 你有看见我的眼镜吗?
Lorraine, have you seen my glasses?
在你的皮夹克里 亲爱的
They're in your suede jacket, honey.
马丁 怎么了? 你不是和朋友到湖边去了?
Marty, what's wrong? We thought you went to the lake.
你穿着这身衣服到湖边去?
You wore that to the lake?
谢天谢地 你们全恢复正常了
Thank God you guys are all back to normal.
马丁 你在扮谁? 克林特·伊斯特伍德?
Marty, who are you supposed to be? Clint Eastwood?
没错 我得去找詹妮弗
Right. I gotta go get Jennifer.
我很喜欢你这顶帽子 马丁
I really like that hat, Marty.
谢了 贝夫
Thanks, Biff.
詹妮弗
Jennifer.
Jen.
詹妮弗
Jennifer.
马丁
Marty.
我做了一个最可怕的梦
I had the worst nightmare.
马丁 我做的那个梦好逼真
Marty, that dream I had is so real.
那是个关于未来的梦
It was about the future.
关于我们
About us.
而且你还被炒鱿鱼了
And you got fired.
慢着 你说我被炒鱿鱼 是什么意思?
Wait a minute. What do you mean I got fired?
"希尔戴尔"
"Hilldale."
希尔戴尔! 是我们住的地方
Hilldale! This is where we live.
我是说 这是我们以后住的地方
I mean, this is where we're going to live.
在将来
Someday.
马丁 那是一场梦 不是吗?
Marty, it was a dream, wasn't it?
嘿
Hey.
是马丁大哥呢
The big M.
近来如何? 麦佛莱
How's it hanging, McFly?
尼德斯
Hey, Needles.
好正点的车子 让我看看它有什么本事
Nice set of wheels. Let's see what she can do.
到下一个红绿灯为止
Next green light.
不 谢了
No, thanks.
怎么了? 你没胆?
What's the matter? Chicken?
胆小鬼麦佛莱
Chicken McFly.
马丁 不!
Marty, don't.
坐稳了
Grab hold of something.
加油! 加油!
Come on! Get on!
加油! 要他好看
Yeah, go! Go, go, go!
你是故意这么做的?
Did you do that on purpose?
你想我会笨得想跟那个王八蛋比快?
Yeah, you think I'm stupid enough to race that asshole?
我的天 我可能会撞上那辆劳斯莱斯的
Jeez! I would have hit that Rolls-Royce.
(你被炒鱿鱼了)
字消失了
It erased.
你说得对 确实没剩下什么
You're right. There's not much left.
博士永远不会回来了
Doc's never coming back.
我会很怀念他的 珍
I'm sure gonna miss him, Jen.
到底是怎么回事?
What the hell?
博士!
Doc!
马丁!
Marty!
博士! 博士!
Doc! Doc!
马丁 它是由蒸汽推动的!
Marty, it runs on steam!
见过我的全家福 克蕾拉 你已经认识了
Meet the family. Clara, you know.
嗨! 马丁!
Hi, Marty!
夫人!
Ma'am!
以及我的小犬们
These are our boys.
儒勒 还有凡尔纳
Jules and Verne.
儿子们 这两位是马丁和詹妮弗
Boys, this is Marty and Jennifer.
博士 我还以为我再也见不到你
Doc, I thought I'd never see you again.
一个优秀的科学家是闲不住的
You can't keep a good scientist down.
毕竟 我得回来接爱因斯坦
After all, I had to come back for Einstein,
而且 我不希望你为我担心
and, well, I didn't want you to be worried about me.
我给你带来了一个纪念品
I brought you a little souvenir.
这太棒了! 博士 谢了!
It's great, Doc. Thanks.
布朗博士? 我从未来带回来这张纸条
Dr. Brown, I brought this note back from the future,
现在它上面的字消失了
and now it's erased.
它当然消失了
Of course it's erased.
但这是表示什么呢?
But what does that mean?
这表示你们的未来尚未成定局
It means your future hasn't been written yet.
谁都一样
No one's has.
你们的未来是掌握在你们的手上
Your future is whatever you make it.
所以好好把握吧 你们两个都一样
So make it a good one, both of you.
我们会的 博士!
We will, Doc!
退后点!
Stand back!
好了 小子们 往后面一点!
All right, boys, buckle up!
对了 博士 你们现在要去哪? 回到未来去?
Hey, Doc, where are you going now? Back to the future?
不 已经去过了
No, already been there.